





Pankaj Kumar Pankaj Kumar Reatured 7 Seeking roles in Project Management, Incident Management, Escalation Management, Change Management, Configuration Management, System Administration, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Technical Support, Redhat Linux, Cost Control, Networking, ITIL, SQL

Current Designation: Associate Tech Specialist Total Experience: 12 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tech Mahindra Limited Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Role: Tech Support Engnr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Tech Support Engineer, Project Management, Incident Management, Escalation Management, Change Management, Configuration Management, System Administration, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Technical Support, Redhat Linux, Cost Control, Networking, ITIL

Verified : Email - id

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Highly effective Leader/Technical Specialist with over 13 years of experience, specializing in Deployment and providing application support in various projects. I can handle the work pressure and make the client happy by providing good support. My greatest strength is to take ownership and maintain the healthy environment at the work place.

Work Experience

Tech Mahindra Limited as Associate Tech Specialist

Sep 2013 to Till Date

Handling all client escalations and resolving their issues on time. And part of Outage management team where need to resolve issues as early as possible.

Conducted Webinar/training on Basic linux, Ansible, Big data and tricky technique for applications monitoring for Techmahindra Employees

Actively part of Azure Migration calls for various applications.

Project Name: Thunderbird Apache and ICS 01A

Client Name: American Telephone & Telegraph Systems (AT&T)

The Project aimed at Supporting, deployment and Maintenance of Unix, Hadoop System and Windows based applications used by AT&T's users. We are providing L2 support. We received Tickets from the users and based on the severity of the tickets, we have to resolve the issue. We have to make 100% availability of the applications. Set the nagios alert for the application.

- Handling all azure migration calls and providing all details related to application.
- Work on automation for the application.
- Conducting location meeting for Noida.
- Attending client and user community calls for enhancement of the application.
- Prepare Top 10 application report and looks for any automation.
- Supporting 20 applications and mainly doing key role in NISE-CORE and PME application.
- Using Ansible to do the configuration and deployment part since 1.5 years.
- Creating alerts for applications which informed immediately the issue in the application.
- Responsible for reflection X attachment configuration for XGUI.
- Providing On-Call support during off business hours and weekends.
- Trained new resources for the team, conducted webinar and training sessions across all the clusters
- Handling audit process for all the employees at Noida location.

Guavus Network System Private Ltd as System Administrator Jan 2012 to Aug 2013

Supporting the Depleyment team

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

- Supporting the Deployment team.
- Up-gradation of respective tall mapple Products.
- Mapping Dell storage device with linux server's.
- Apache configuration and setup the server.
- Network Planning and maintenance of Linux server's.
- Backups of servers on storage and do shell scripting for automation.
- Configuration of Nagios for generating the alerts of the servers.
- Connectivity of Equallogic and md storage with servers.
- Configuring the server and boot from SAN.
- Worked on Dell Blade Chasis and Cisco UCS.
- Creation of Van for better network performance

HCL Technolgies Ltd. as Specialist Network

Sep 2010 to Dec 2011

Prepared onsite production and test system of HSP (High Speed Proxy) or WAP gateway for Orange Slovakia Client in Brno (Czech Republic).

- Deployment of ACISION Specific products like HSP(High Speed proxy) or GPRS gateway,DPS(Direct Push Server) in differ modes and configurations as per required by customer
- Up-gradation of respective ACISION Operating System-NGP(ACISION Customized Redhat Linux Platform) products (HSP),DPS and relevant services,Licenses and Packages.
- Support work of troubles hooting incidents when sitting at base location by remotely accessing the client servers using HCL's Stepping Stone server
- Integration and Configuration of Linux server's based Production/Test Nodes. Installation of NGP,LDAP,HSP,WSB,CWMS,DPS,YUM Repository and their Configuration in OAM,Traffic.Cluster networks by assigning IP's according to site IP Plan.
- Backup and restoration of Data and Logs with the help of TAR and BZIP2 utility, Taking Back up of the old log files, SDR's and use it when required.
- Troubleshooting of Linux based applications and services at the time of Planned Activity.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Information Technology) from Dehradun Institute of Technology, Dehradun (U.A.) in 2006

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Engineer

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

	Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
	Red hat Linux, Ubuntu, VLAN			
	Tall Mapple, Windows XP, PL/SQL,			
	JBoss, LVM, RAID, Asteris, Hadoop			
	Dell Storage, Cisco Switches			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.